# **Dan Pathammavong**

Full Stack Software Engineer

612.418.0629 | patha037@umn.edu | linkedin.com/in/danpatha/ | danpatha.github.io/Portfolio/

#### **SUMMARY**

Creative and analytical full stack software engineer, leveraging diverse video production experiences to the tech field to create and manage full stack web applications. Approaching projects with an inclusive and usability focus, using technologies like JavaScript, React, Redux, Saga, and SQL.

#### **SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- Express.js
- jQuery
- Material UI
- C#
- React.js

- Node.js
- SQL
- Redux-Saga
- Figma
- Software testing & debugging

- Time management
- Creative problem solving
- Communication
- Team collaboration
- Negotiations
- Public speaking

#### LANGUAGES:

- English
- Laotian

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

# **MinneLeagues**

- MinneLeagues is a user-friendly web application that allows users to search adult recreational sport leagues across the Twin Cities and beyond all in one place, which streamlines the traditional process.
- Users are able to search for various sports leagues near them using a multitude of criteria, like sport, competitive level, and day of the week. Users can also read information about the leagues, share it with others or themselves, and click an external link where they can sign up. And admin users have the functionality to add, edit, and delete leagues.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, SQL, Redux-Saga, and Figma.

# **Faceless Pro**

- Faceless Pro is an early-seed startup in the Twin Cities and a blind recruitment job board. The goal of Faceless Pro is to eliminate unconscious bias and discrimination against job applicants.
- Collaborated with a team of developers to offer job-seekers the ability to apply for jobs incognito, by concealing all personal information like name, age, race, and gender. Instead of their name, applicants are given a random identifier that includes a combination of an animal and an object, like Elephant Paper in the hiring process. Employers can post, delete and edit jobs. Applicants can search, save and apply for jobs. Employers and applicants have the ability to communicate through a messaging system. Lastly, applicants can reveal their identity, choosing which employers and when to do so, providing them complete control of their anonymity.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, React, CSS, Git, PostgreSQL, Multer, Axios, and Material UI.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Software Engineer (Student)

# Prime Digital Academy | August 2022 - January 2023

- Full-time accelerated program teaching modern technologies such as JavaScript, React, Node, Express,
  SQL. Additional training in diversity, equity, & inclusion, professional development, and public speaking.
- Developed two full-stack React applications; including a 2-week independent project and 3-week collaborative project for a client.

### Freelance Videographer

#### Self-Employed | January 2019 - July 2022

- Orchestrated and led two shoots a week, including all video production planning, shot lists, camera operation, shooting, editing, and publishing.
- Routinely surpassed client expectations and deadlines by continuously exhibiting a tenacious willingness to improve.
- Negotiated and coordinated with 10-12 key organization members and 1-2 clients on the systemization of video content structure, schedule, and details.
- Demonstrated a deep level of focus and a composed patience to projects. And possessing a malleably adaptive approach to the inevitable changes in the production process.

# Videographer

# Richfield Historical Society | January 2021 - December 2021

- Educated and communicated with 4-6 board members and key partners on strategizing video and photo content for accelerated results.
- Planned and executed three weekly video shows, while meeting all deadlines and coordinating social media content schedules.
- Generated an increase in social media engagement and views by 30%. Successfully boosted monthly donations by over 50%.
- Identified areas for brand growth and utilized motion graphics and theme music to help customize, redesign, and amplify the brand identity.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

#### Prime Digital Academy | January 2023

- Learned hands-on using various languages and technologies with an engineering instructor.
- Developed full stack web applications individually and with peers.
- Attended professional networking events and mentorship meetings.

Bachelor of Science: Family Social Science

# University of Minnesota - Twin Cities | December 2020

- CEHD Global Discovery Scholarship, 2019
- Dean's List, Fall 2017